so part of my anti-mlm
rabbit hole that i've fallen down is
i've started following some youtube
creators that are in the auntie emma
movement one of whom i found through
that is is illuminati
her name is blair i will link to the
video i am talking about
in the in the description so today's
video that she did is not about mlms
it's about trans ableism
and trans ableism for those that that
don't know what it is
is somebody whose identity of who they
are is a disability but their body
doesn't match that
so they feel they should be blind but
they're not blind they feel they should
be missing a certain limb but they're
not missing that certain limb
there are some people in that community
that do it for attention and other
people who have and she
separates the two out and says one we
should have compassion for and the other
ones are the worst of the worst
i don't agree with that um i think
that our entire society
is ableist as and all of our other
isms
stem from our ableism racism
says this group of people is x
because they're y right they have this
trait because they're black
ableism says it matters at all why does
it matter
if if a group of people is lazy why does
it matter if a group of people has less
of an iq
why does it matter if a group of people
is more or less athletic
i'm not okay in racism i'm just saying
that if we were more if we didn't have
any ableism we wouldn't have racism if
we didn't have ableism we wouldn't have
homophobia or sexism because we would
see the individual instead of the gender
and the race and the sexuality and
however they showed up in
any of their capacities on the spectrum
of ability and traits
they would be acceptable and so when i
hear people
talk about trans ableism all of the
ableism comes out
in today in this pandemic i cannot tell
you the amount of times i have heard
people be like well it's just people
with pre-existing conditions
if we said that about any other group of
people
we would see it for the racist sexist
homophobia it was
right as much as people might be acting
in a systemically racist way that this
that this pandemic seems to kill more
black and brown people
than it does caucasian people um
no one i haven't heard a single as
racist as our world is say well whatever
who cares it's just killing black and
brown people
right they are absolutely saying that
about pre-existing conditions
it's just the feeble weak burdens of
society that it's taking out
and this is where i absolutely disagree
with society's version of disability
i think our disabilities our unique
stance
place in the world our unique lived
experience whether our disabilities are
acquired or were born with them
give us a unique perspective and so our
disabilities are actually a gift
to society if we're able to give it the
issue is society set up for able-bodied
neurotypical emotionally
able to handle their emotions people
it's not set up for those with emotional
disabilities with physical disabilities
with
with mental disabilities with
neurodivergence it's not
and so i trigger a lot of people
who are in the toxic positivity movement
my family being some of them
when they're like well if you just
thought better thoughts you'd heal
yourself
and i don't think that's true
one because i am very positive thinking
i've tried all those things and it
didn't improve it
i have to save the world to save myself
and i'm good with that
i so it's like just be grateful and
think positively i'm like i am grateful
for every experience i've been through
i'm grateful for my chronic fatigue i'm
grateful for my fibrobiology i'm
grateful for my brain tumors because
they help make me who i
am and what i'm here to do i'm grateful
for my tbi
after my brain surgery even though i
think my cert my the doctors the medical
system
i got it from incompetence a little bit
um
i'm still grateful for it it's helped me
see the world differently because my
brain is different from morning to night
my brain's different from when i was 24
to when i was 30.
i can see the world differently because
of it and so
i don't think people with disabilities
are a burden on society i think we're a
gift to society and that changes
everything because my version
my take on transableism people who have
the
wait why do i i feel i shouldn't have an
arm and i do
right i feel i should be blind and i'm
not this is weird this is not my body
is potentially because they came to this
world to live that experience
to give their gift and they're not
livi living out that experience so it's
a very strange like wait no like there's
a part of them
that something didn't happen that was
supposed to i don't know that's just my
take on it of how i can see it
this could be the case right if i had
come to this planet to do what i'm here
to do which is powerful things
and i somehow didn't have chronic
fatigue and fibromyalgia so i was still
working
the universe might kick me in the butt
and do something else now if i went out
of my way to do that yes then i'd be
trans ableist
if i was like how do i fix how do i
create it but there's
your subconscious and living into the
world that just ends up
ends up happening but that there's a
difference between people who have
a liv that they were born with their
disability and people who have acquired
it
and so she talks about in her there's a
woman who got in an accident is now in a
wheelchair
and is like well how dare they be like
that because i could cure myself i would
that's your own ableism why should they
have to deal with your own ableism
because i know a ton of people and she's
not wrong for feeling that way it's her
lived experience
right the woman in a wheelchair being
like i would cure myself if i could she
probably finds beauty and love in that
in that space as well
but i know people who liter list their
accident they got them in a wheelchair
as their single most defining moment
that they would never change
ever because it helped them be who they
are and find their purpose and help them
eat the love of their life and help them
in whatever way that it helped them
and so there's a big difference between
somebody acquiring a disability and
being like how dare anyone want this
this is a burden burden burden on me a
burden on society
so how dare you because you're not
seeing the flip side
of the gift that every disability gives
to the society
the gift of having a different lived
experience
having a society that does not work for
you whatever that disability is so that
you can help
fix society society is not set up for
that and this is the problem
we're in a very competitive world and so
people with disabilities are at a
disadvantage in a competitive world and
whatever advantage we do
have we need to hold on to in a
competitive world
right i'm a spoonie i have to really
care about how i spend my energy because
of that
i've had to come up with some ingenious
ways to save energy and spend energy
that would work for anyone anywhere
if they did it to my extreme they would
be trans ambulance
but if they used it a little bit used it
a little bit to
find where they want to do stuff and do
it when they when they
feel the motivation to do it if they
took more downtime if they did what i do
they would probably get a benefit out of
it
but in a competitive world why would i
help them
in a cooperative world giving them my
gifts of what i've learned from this
position
would help me because then they get to
show up better they get to have more
energy to do whatever they're here to do
in the world which would help me
but in a society that we're only
competitive that's a problem
i do want to touch on um a blair is very
clear
to cut to separate the people who are
doing it as because their body doesn't
align with what they feel it should be
um and calls it out as a mental disorder
we have different i have a different
view of that which i think i've
mentioned in here
um which is not i wouldn't expect any of
them to to to see my view that's just
one way that it could have existed
uh versus the people who are doing it
just for attention
and she her wording exactly was um
they can burn in hell but she's that
they but if what you're
do if other people if you're making
other people feel worse about themselves
and it actively costs society you are a
problematic person
that is my view of what influencer
culture is
and as blair herself is an influencer
she has
over half a million subscribers i'm not
saying she should stop that
but as a society influencers having that
much power that that many people listen
to them
that if you can't edit a video like i
can't you're not listened to even though
you have world freaking saving problems
i mean
solutions that there's
a problem with this and if you watch the
social dilemma where the algorithms
working in that way
their influencers are this is my biggest
problem with influencer culture
if an influencer has a choice
to follow their own inner guidance and
do a topic they really care about
but they know it's going to get crickets
they know no one's going to watch it
they're not going to make that content
that's too much work
versus they're going to follow the
the algorithm they're going to follow
the thing that's going to get them the
most views they're going to pick that
one and making all of those decisions
continuously is going to make you into a
different person
you're not becoming your own most
authentic self you're becoming your most
influence yourself and they're two
different paths some people can figure
out how to do both some people's
natural authentic path is going to be
influencer
they're gonna they're gonna be beautiful
and charismatic and articulate and be
able to to
um edit and be able to get to that role
but then it starts to change who you
are or you or you're extremely strong to
be able to do it even the people who
first get involved in it
the reason i'm on youtube is to change
the world and yet i have
very few subscribers the people like me
if they don't have a world changing idea
aren't on youtube which means you don't
get to hear the introverts side actually
a lot of
youtubers are introverts but even when
they're on camera they don't appear to
be
right they're not showing you the
introvert side they're kind of showing
you their extrovert self
and so to me i want diversity at the
individual authentic level
i want to be able to create a world that
works for
every part of every spectrum so whether
you
have a disability that you acquired
whether you had a disability you
you chose to acquire whether you have a
disability you were born with
that you can live your best life because
you are equipped with the tools
to live to define what your best life is
and move towards it and live it
and nobody else gets to define that for
you nobody else gets to say oh you're in
a wheelchair you must want to get out of
it that
let's pray for you to get out of that
let's that's all we're going to
concentrate on
like to my family it looks like i've
given up because i'm no longer
interested in what they think is going
to cure
fatigue and pain like guys it'll go when
it's meant to
what a slap in the face to the people
who gave me who gave it to me before i
got here
to say that this isn't this isn't the
life i'm supposed to live this is my
problem with not just influence or
toxic positivity culture is they don't
want you to be authentic they want you
to be their version of authentic which
is the furthest thing from authentic
that that no you're supposed to think
positively so you cure yourself
you're supposed to think positively so
you become rich
i'm like right but what if my best
lessons what if what i'm here to do is
from a place
of illness what if i'm from a place of
disability from a place of being in
poverty
from a place of having not the resources
or anxiety
this is where i'm supposed to live it
from this is how i'm living out my
purpose it doesn't mean i don't want it
to heal
but it also means i love where i am
and that is more healing than anything
any doctor any
cure can give me is to be happy in where
i
am and anyone can be happy in where they
are
not if there's a only if this happens i
will be happy
isn't true happiness and so i have
tapped into happiness that triggers the
out of other people are like you
can't be you're not rich you can't be
you're not healed you can't be
i'm happy i really truly am and that
means allowing the full spectrum of
emotions i also get angry i also get sad
i also get scared
and i showcase those too so your first
time on this channel
and you want to hang out because you
like my personality please like and
subscribe
i am here to create a world that works
for everyone solution raising on this
channel is my current
my current version ironically i am
creating an mlm
because just like i pointed out how her
her
her being judgmental about these people
seeking attention
i can see how it's very directly or tied
to influencer
me being judgmental towards mlms of
course spouted the idea that
that's a game b omni-win mlm that i am
uh exploring with people tomorrow
if you're anti-mlm i promise you it's a
good one i promise you
it it got it passed is my anti-mlm self
and i would love to have some anti-mlm
people actually critique it
once it's ready for for public
consumption so
please like and subscribe and i'll see
you next time and please be kind to each
other we all
oh we've been on solution raising today
kerry was talking about people on the
fringes of society and i'm like
everyone's on the fringes
because even if game a even if this
world works for you 99
there's still one percent it doesn't and
together we could solve that one percent
for you
together we if 99 of the world doesn't
work for you we can solve it together
and improve it it's not about creating
utopia
it's about creating real lasting
improvement and the more we're able to
do that together
the less risk there is the more powerful
it is
and the faster this all happens thank
you